Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/namanaravi-0511b412 (LinkedIn) www.hirebetter.in (Personal)

Top Skills

Talent Acquisition
Innovation Management
Strategic Sourcing

Languages

English Telugu

Namana Ravi

Sr Technical Recruiter at Microsoft India(immediately available) Hyderabad

Summary

PROFILE AT A GLANCE

Owned full-cycle recruiting / Talent Acquisition interviewed, offered, negotiated and closed candidates for assigned requisitions

Sourcing resumes through Head Hunting and Job Portals

Executed strategic sourcing techniques to include a variety of resources such as internet, advertising, employment agencies, internal databases, employee referrals, direct sourcing and campus recruitment.

Extensive experience with multiple Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS).

Developed a strong relationship with Business Unit Heads, hiring managers, stake holders and

Business directors to encourage a partnership in filling open requisitions.

Experience

Microsoft Senior Technical Recruiter July 2015 - Present (5 years 2 months) Gachibowli

AIR Worldwide Lead - Talent Aquisition July 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 1 month) Hyderabad Area, India

AIR Worldwide (Product Company)

AIR Worldwide (AIR) is the scientific leader and most respected provider of risk modeling software and consulting services. AIR founded the catastrophe modeling industry in 1987 and today models the risk from natural catastrophes and terrorism in more than 90 countries. More than 400 insurance, reinsurance, financial, corporate, and government clients rely on AIR software and services for catastrophe risk management, insurance-linked securities, detailed site-specific wind and seismic engineering analyses, and agricultural risk management. AIR, a Verisk Analytics (Nasdaq:VRSK) business, is headquartered in Boston with additional offices in North America, Europe, and Asia.

Key Responsibilities:

Managing end to end recruiting process in fulfilling technical hiring and also ensuring a smooth and positive candidate experience.

Partnering with Business & Respective Hiring Managers to understand their requirements and fulfill the same within stipulated time.

Actively sourcing Passive candidates through Social Networking sites like Linkedin, and Facebook etc.

Working closely with HRBP's on Compensation & Offer Approval process to generate the offer roll outs for the successful candidates.

Implementing effective staffing strategies to focus on recruiting the most qualified candidates and provide a qualified and diverse candidate pool.

Ensure in providing great Customer(Candidates & Hiring Manager/Business Leaders) experience by effectively interacting with them and updating them status in the shortest possible time

Managing the relationships with hiring managers by building relationships & earn trust within each business unit. Doing this by maintaining reports and weekly meetings to share update on each open requisition.

Actively coordinating weekend events for different job families across locations.

Hire Better Recruitment Services LLP Founder September 2011 - June 2014 (2 years 10 months) Hyderabad Area, India

Company: Hire Better Recruitment Services LLP

A Recruitment Consulting firm with an attempt to retain the actual Standards of recruitment Agency by playing a true role of a Consultant by assisting the

companies in finding the right talent from the market to the Businesses. We at HireBetter highly focused on:

- # Robust Screening Methodologies,
- # Selling the Clients' Brand
- # High candidate engagement processes and
- # High control on Pre-Joining Attrition.

Key Responsibilities:

 Develop and drive the staffing strategy / Recrutiment Strategy and practices to fit Client needs

and to provide a qualified and diverse candidate pool.

• Develop multiple sourcing strategies for multiple Client needs depending on complexity of the

position to hire by effectively using all the sourcing channels Naukri, Monster, Social Networking

Sites and Internal ATS by posting the Jobs, and Employee Referrals.

 Work with hiring managers to ensure recruiting activities have the appropriate prioritization, are

being acted on in a timely manner and are ultimately selecting the best candidate considering a

mix of culture match, skills, abilities, experiences and diversity.

 Regularly provide crisp and incisive reports to hiring managers on open requirement status and

the achievement of core metrics.

- Connecting with passive candidates for reference generation, future requirements
- Setting up client expectations based on the market intelligence.
- Technical screening of profiles to ensure role fitment.
- Active participation in phone screening and HR interviews to select most suitable candidate.
- Giving prospective candidates a holistic picture of the role and setting up expectations right at the
- Involved in salary negotiations, pre and post offer management process.
- Ensuring the best candidate experience throughout the hiring process.
- Creating concise reports for business and staffing manager.

HCL Technologies

beginning.

Talent Acquisition Executive February 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 8 months)

HCL Technologies Limited

HCL Technologies Limited is a global IT services company headquartered in Noida, India. It offers services including software consulting, enterprise transformation, remote infrastructure management, engineering and R&D services, and business process outsourcing (BPO). TOP 5 IT Giants in India Key Responsibilities:

- Management of the complete recruitment / Talent Acquisition life-cycle for sourcing the best talent from diverse sources after identification of manpower requirements.
- Regular Interaction with the hiring managers for understanding the requirement and business needs.
- Initial screening of potential candidates and setting up face-to-face, VC and phone interviews.
- Updating the recruitment database accordingly and providing daily and weekly reports on the recruitment status to the top management.
- Having periodic review meetings with the hiring managers and group heads to discuss the status and plan strategies.
- Mentoring trainees in recruitment process
- Planning and coordinating recruitment events across various cities in India on a periodic basis.
- Conducting Hiring event screened candidates and also organize in-house interviews.
- Handle salary negotiations and compensation administration in line with organisation's C&B standards.
- Assertive and influence all stakeholders to act with a sense of urgency on staffing matters.

Wipro Infotech

Employee Retention -Academic Project January 2008 - February 2008 (2 months)

Done an organization wide survey for the teams in Hyderabad at Wipro Infotech. Analyzed various factors from employee perspective to understand their statisfaction levels as well to understand the factors that would lead to better engagement of the resources.

ICICI Prudential

Summer Sales Training(Internship)
July 2007 - September 2007 (3 months)

Got Trained on a financial product of ICICI and was part of a sales team, majorly involved in selling the product.

Education

Bhavans Vivekananda College

Master of Business Administration; 05

Bachelors, Hr; Computer

Science · (2006 - 2008)

Govt. Autonomous College

Bachelor of Science, Computers · (2002 - 2005)

R.K., Vivekananda Vidya Nikethan